Alright, welcome back.
Let me share.
Bonnie got the diagram to render.
So from here we can see that here is um.
Vertical slice one,
which is the one we just completed.
And you can see that.
All of these slices can be implemented in
parallel once we've completed the VSO one.
In addition to that,
we have a VSO 2 which is a basic
arithmetic capability and that we have a
VSO 3 which is dependent upon.
That so taking on VSO 2 is a good idea so
that we can proceed to our critical path
here that for all the things that must be
done before other things can be completed
and that will allow us to execute.
And implement additional vertical slices
as we go along.
So let's go ahead and assign.
Some of these tasks, somebody,
if somebody could pick up VSO 2,
that would be a good idea and any of
these others that are on the first tier,
which is basically we're starting here
with 781316.
Are all good candidates for
implementation, so.
Let's go ahead and and assign these work
items also.
Al,
I saw that you posted that you've
completed slices one through 10.
How did that go for you?
Alright.
Right. Any questions?
Oh, all right. No, no worries, though.
That's fine.
3:00 AM You win the Perseverance award.
Thanks for sticking this out.
I'm proud of you.
All right. Any any questions on this?
Anybody have any issues assigning a
ticket and picking it up?
Can you post in chat which ones you you
have which you've assigned so I can get a
sense of what we're working on?
I I think that slice 7 and slice 6 are.
Uh, like swapped in terms of name.
Really.
On this diagram.
Let me look at the issues.
Chris.
The six and seven,
so six is delete the last digit.
And on the diagram.
Where is 6?
That's over here. Keyboard input.
And then there is um.
So backspace, delete the last digit is,
you know, it looks keyboard input. Yeah,
you're right. That's interesting.
Alright, so I'm gonna go ahead and ask.
AI to take a look at that and see what it
reports back.
Yes.
So VS 06 and VS 07.
But the the ESO 6 bill says titles are.
Select.
On the dial room.
And then ask it to explain.
So.
It agrees that they're swapped.
And it's think something is interesting.
And it also found a VSO 8.
As I think that's OK, so.
And I'm gonna ask it then.
But to to verify that all the.
Slice.
Titles. Uh, correct.
In the telegram.
And let me go ahead and.
View the diagram again.
3.
And we can see here looks like VS 067 is
here and 06 is correct.
Delete the last digit backspace.
And here is 7 keyboard input.
All right, well,
so let's see what happens with the
analysis.
Anybody have any questions?
Everybody making progress?
Any issues that we can?
Discuss.
John, were you going to, um,
go over a prompt about showcasing?
I can. I did create a an instruction file.
Is that what you're looking for?
No.
No,
I I thought you before the break you had
mentioned something about that part of
the process showcasing the.
Well, if you complete a,
if you've completed,
Twice.
if you completed a slice,
then I'd like you to showcase that slice
to the rest of the team.
OK.
So just so if you've once you've
completed a slice and you think it's
ready for showcasing,
then go ahead and raise your hand and
we'll.
And we'll we'll have you demonstrate it
for us.
So it looked like there's quite a few
mistakes here.
Well, it says some of them are,
some are fixed.
Looks like 1234 and five are all
different and it made some minor
improvements to the document for some
other titles.
So let's uh preview that.
And we can see that we're getting a
different error here with the.
Dependency graph. Again, I always find.
Occasional errors with the the
implementation of graphs.
Uh, wants to update go.
And uh, let's see,
I wanna add into the chat now.
Yeah,
and the first copy always seems to fail.
2.
So it's gonna take a look at that and see
if we can fix the parsing error.
So it it looks like something got cut off
and it's gonna fix that.
And you can see that it found that was
missing a closing quote.
Right.
So let's go ahead and view that again.
And we need to.
Not finding grass.
Well, we still have an error,
a parsing problem.
It's a map.
again.
And with copy and paste.
So let me go ahead and.
Still having a a problem with that same
one.
So it thinks it's got it fixed.
So let's take a look at that.
Same error. It doesn't look like it's.
Got the same.
Where is our PWA?
So that that looks right.
And now we have a rendered documents.
2.
Let's go back and look at our issues.
Let me look at all the issues.
All right, so.
There's a feature that's moved in.
That's that's our first slice.
Looks like Chris is working on the.
Slice 4.
And these are ones I deleted. Yeah, Chris.
I'm on mute. I'm ready to showcase 4.
All right, go right ahead.
Um.
And share the screen.
Yeah,
I'm going to share my laptop screen
because this might be a little unruly for
anyone who's on a laptop. Big screens.
There we go. OK.
And I don't see that anybody's assigned a
an issue to them.
So if you have or if you're working on
one,
please assign it so that we know that you
are.
So go ahead, Chris.
Yeah, so um,
the tests or the the showcase items, um,
I'll,
I'll just run through those and that's,
oh gosh, the screens.
I've got two wide.
Wide screens,
so when I'm moving stuff around,
sometimes it's jumpy.
So these are the items equals and result,
so equals and enter.
On these calculations I'm just going to
run through these using the enter key
OK.
following order of operations.
Edge case 10 / 0 shows that can't divide
and then precision, so float.
OK.
And I've just be because I'm more
familiar with cursor and I have the
cursor full and able to use all their
models.
I've been using that and using the same
kind.
It has a lot of the same stuff like
agents and instructions and stuff like
that. So just.
Alright.
Supplanted those into cursor 5 + 3 equals
8.
OK.
Enter is giving me a result.
And thus so order of operations.
This doesn't.
You know, backspace,
'cause that's not part of my slice. Um.
Probably me do.
Now.
So 5 + 3 * 2.
115 + 3 multiplied by 211.
Edge case 10 / 0.
I cannot divide by zero.
Try something completely different.
OK, really test it and then float.
All right.
Oh.
Uh.
There we go,
and we're working with float too.
So that's that's the showcase for slice
for order of operations.
OK, so you did 5 + 3 * 2, is that right?
5 + 3,
so 3 * 2 + 5 the order of operations.
All right. OK, that's great.
equals 11. Yeah.
So go ahead and go ahead and merge that
change then.
Yeah.
I didn't have to do any development
myself. It's great.
Yeah,
I just saw a a post on LinkedIn where you
know where they the the the value
proposition for coding is changing from,
you know having high skills in terms of
writing the code towards.
High skills in terms of defining the
specifications and being able to,
you know,
express that intent that the A I can take
on.
And I I tend to agree that that's where
where the skills are going to be going to
be.
It's it's like think the critical
thinking part of it is where all where
that.
All the activity is gonna be now and not
just the, you know,
figuring out the code syntax in order to
express that intent.
All right,
so is anybody else working on a slice?
Raise your hand.
Hey, Matt, what do you want?
What are you working on?
Christopher's working on one. That's good.
Which ones are you working on?
Working on that delete last digit,
the the A I was also confused and
All right.
accidentally put in the the keyboard
input implementation,
so it seems to be consistently mixing
those two up.
Mm.
Right.
How's it going, Matt?
You're making progress.
Yeah, I am.
I don't know if you saw this in developer
circles,
but this blog entry was shared in mind
about a guy who's a Blogger,
relatively influential,
rejected a PR from a I and a I wrote a
hit piece against him on.
On their blog.
That sounds.
Scary.
Yeah.
All right. So anybody else interested?
Dan,
you have you picked up another another
slice?
Uh, no, I didn't.
OK.
It's sort of long for the ride now.
All right.
So um.
Let me go back and look at what's taken.
John,
would you be able because I don't have
the copilot review,
but I've got my PR in there now.
I was wondering if you're able to run the
code review.
You know, let me uh, which one is it 7?
04.
04 OK, let me look at it.
Looks like it's the only current open.
Yeah.
Alright, so let me bring up.
Uh, GitHub.
And look at the pull requests.
So yeah, I can request that review.
Super. Thanks.
So let's take a look at what you've got.
All right.
No change the.
Looking at the prompt file,
it made a change the prompt file and it
added some implementation.
This is related to.
Uh, correcting the math precision.
Uh.
Interesting.
Yeah,
it asked it to merge the issue with the
prompt because there were some things
missed between the two.
OK.
Yeah, that would be something to look at.
All right.
I'll mark that reviewed.
So here's some new code.
This is the unit test for the.
The calculator.
So here it's checking for.
That the.
That the actual is equals to the expected
for the asserting the expected label.
So that's not even part,
that's just part of the asserting parse.
Here's the critical tests.
And we're looking at testing 5 + 3 is
equal to 8,
so we can see that we're passing tick to
the calculate function there.
So these tests are looking good.
Some edge cases.
X3X +3.
I -, 5. Yeah, those are edge cases.
I see that we've added in here a accept
this file is viewed.
Added a query selector.
It looks like some substantial changes to
the Jason.
Yeah.
Right.
My guess is that we're gonna start to see
some conflicts related to.
files that are going to be modified by
Uh, separate level, level sizes.
I.
Yeah, I can approve it.
And.
Copilot still thinking about it.
All right.
Pretty cool that you can see the thought
process.
Of the review.
You want to share and show us?
Hello.
Yeah, yeah,
it's it's in the the comments part or the
Let me look at it.
Let's see if I can show it.
the history of the PR.
You're talking.
You can see where it was requested and
then there's a view session, yeah.
Yeah.
So it's identifying different things.
Yeah,
that's quite a process if we see that
we're generating a lot of.
Um.
A lot of issues with with the code that's
being created.
That would be a signal or that we would
want to go back to our instruction file
and see if there's instruction files in
our prompts to see if there's something
here that we need to.
Improve so that we get closer to a clean
code from the initial PR.
So it reviewed this. Um.
That's the session. Let's go back to the.
Pull request.
Yeah,
it's still not done though with the Uh
review.
OK.
It's interesting that Slice 2 hasn't been
implemented,
but I was able to do that in what I had
put together.
You are you are able to implement to #2
is that what you're saying along with
Not well, I don't know if it.
I don't know if it implemented it cause
people?
#2 is just being able to input the digit
with a keyboard.
Right.
And I was able to do that in slice 4.
I think that was added in.
During slice one.
Was that?
That because that was one of the things
the review pointed out is that it looked
like the prompt for slice one was trying
to to do stuff that's from VSO 2.
Scope creep.
Yeah,
because it member was asking us that we
should split the split slice one into two
slices because there was a there's a bit
of a conflict in the definition where the
the script the the title and I think said
that it was just supposed to display the
0.
And slated and the number in slice one
and and it was actually allowing for
input as well.
And so that would be something that we
would want to try to catch in the review
of the.
Of the the slice implementation plan and
if we noticed that that there was a a
conflict there,
we could then go back and split them up
into separate slices, you know,
with the idea that our implementation
plan, you know,
might have an issue with it that we would.
Need to address in order for us to get a
clean slices.
So it may be that we if we try to
implement too,
it'll it'll basically tell us that that
that implementation has already been done.
So it's doing a lot of thinking to review
those these changes as it finished that
review.
It.
Still says it's not.
Let me just refresh the page just to make
sure.
And it looks like that's still going on.
And then I chose there was an option to
review the.
View the reviewed changes.
Oh,
it's just telling us that I've I've
viewed them. That's fine.
In Copilot,
it looks like it's actually completed its
review and lets them review comments.
So let's go back to the conversation.
So.
Here's the pull request overview changes
that made reviewed those changes.
And generated 8 comments.
So the first one had to do with Unicode.
That's interesting here.
When clearing an error state in the input
digit,
the code resets the message and the
current value,
but it it leaves the expression tokens
and previous operations intact.
That's a interesting finding.
That's a and it's certainly an edge case
that we didn't catch.
And here's another one that's very
similar.
And notice here we have the commit
suggestion options.
This previously this file previously
contained the required AI provenance
header,
so this goes back to it's missing that.
And uh.
And here we have a constant that's
declared but never used.
Tests cover subtraction.
To the again with the Unicode minus and
an unused function which is a sort equal.
It looks like this is the last one,
which is basically another unused unused
function, so.
Looks like you got a little work to do,
so I'll let you take that on.
And like I said, this is, you know,
if every single pull request that we were
creating is generating request for
modifications,
then I think that that's a that would be
a sign that our instruction files need to
be tightened up a bit and we could
actually feed this information back to.
AI and ask it to update our instruction
files to ensure that this code gets in
the future gets created correctly.
Alright,
so let me know if you want me to submit
another review.
I'm just seeing how cursor might connect
to the PR to work through the comments
itself first I think.
All right. You could also just hit those.
Uh.
Commit the suggestion buttons too.
Anybody else have a comment or a question?
So this this exercise really intended to
try to get a bar real-world experience
and what you're likely to see when you
start to take advantage of these
capabilities in your own organization,
in your own projects.
I tried to merge in Chris's into slice 3
and as expected they're a merge conflict,
so hopefully I'll have a PR shortly.
Yeah.
So this will be something that we would
also want to feed back into our
implementation plan is to.
Try to slit the functionality U into
different files.
So that the features don't conflict with
each other as much.
I mean it may not be possible to do it
completely,
but if we can encapsulate that
functionality into modules of some sort,
then that way.
We won't have those merge conflicts.
I have a question, John.
So I'm looking at the issue that I am
that I that I did with Christopher and
it's still open.
Yeah.
At the very bottom it says you know my
account linked a pull request that will
close this issue,
but it didn't close the issue it doesn't
it seems. So this is #1 BS 01.
Yeah, I'm looking at it right now.
Oh.
Let's see it.
Is it because I didn't assign it to
myself?
It could be that could I it could be.
I just assigned it to myself.
See what happens.
There's also here a close issue option
where we can close it as completed.
OK.
We're looking at the pull request.
That's merged.
Right.
It also could be that we didn't resolve
all the conversations.
So.
So if I wanna make a new issue,
do I just pick one or I just have to make
Yeah, yeah. Well,
the protocol was that if you were working
sure no one else is working on it right?
on something that you assigned it to
yourself.
So I would,
I would say if it if it doesn't,
I see.
if it doesn't have somebody assigned to
it, then it should be free.
for you to pick it up.
OK.
All right, let me go back to the issues.
So it looks like we're working on six and
seven.
and four and three.
And one it should be, uh, completed.
It's still open.
So um.
If you want, Dan,
I'll just go ahead and close this issue.
OK.
Say that it's completed, so that's good.
Oh,
I think when it merged it didn't do a
squash, it did a.
Kept all those individual.
Commits.
Yeah, there's only two, I guess,
so plus the merge.
Right,
that might be a setting that I can change
in the projects.
Uh, using a different account.
And then this will be on.
On our rule sets.
Recent.
Issues.
Allow merge commits as a question.
Auto merge.
I'm not seeing.
Yeah,
I thought there was a way to set the the
default.
I'm not seeing it here.
No, well, I'll find it.
Maybe I can help me with that.
Interesting.
And then so I'll take that.
OK.
Navigate to the way we got that settings
tab, general,
Scroll down to pull requests.
Right.
So and maybe it's just remembers the last
time we selected.
John,
if you want to run the copilot on VS4
again, I've got the changes committed.
All right, we'll do that.
Lisa, thank you.
All right, so.
Yeah, Copilot, please review this.
All right, so we've added a comment and.
Copilot should pick that up.
And.
Pick up that review.
Alright.
Usually takes a little while for it to
recognize that it's been asked to do
something.
Anybody else have some progress to show?
I can show VSO 3 it's.
Not uh.
Big iteration.
Um,
but one thing I was gonna ask is if
'cause I got things a little mixed up
with my GitHub enterprise and my personal
and so I can't actually.
Assign copilot to review my pull request.
Um.
Yeah, yeah. So I can,
I can do that for you.
But.
Then after so I merged in Chris's work,
which was basically everything you see
here except for the clear button and so
the the clear button is so we'll go.
Right.
236 and we clear it back to zero and then
do 3 * 3 and that proves that it cleared
it out.
Right.
I did not.
I haven't gone through the.
The verification steps yet.
Mhm.
This, but this was a pretty easy task.
Luckily the getting the.
The issues from the merge conflicts
resolved. copilot did it on the first try.
There were some issues afterwards where
we had duplicate equals and and plus
signs and things like that,
but it was able to take care of it.
OK.
And so there there were some acceptance
criteria in here for adding the buttons
and things like that,
but that like the plus and and things,
but that was already in 04.
OK.
Um.
So really the only verification steps of
this is that it clears out the state.
Oh.
Right.
Which it does that fine.
So that's it from for slice 3. Um.
All right. So do you have a PR?
Yes, yeah, yeah. I'll post the view.
I see there's two now, so slice three.
Is that true?
Correct.
All right.
Stop sharing them.
I think I need to go back to the other
accounts to get that ability because only
one of my accounts has a subscription and
now I see co-pilots associated with it,
so I will then request that.
So we're looking for color comments on 2
pull requests.
So let me open this in a new tab.
And look at the other PR.
And now I can re request a review.
So now copilot is looking at working on
reviewing of both PRS.
Right, three and four are in progress.
And.
19 files changed.
No, I updated the prompts.
I don't know why it updated like it
updated the slice one prompt.
Why do that?
It looks like it actually just created it.
I think we created a new file still.
Yeah.
Oh, it created it in the prompts.
So mine when I run this,
it's creating them in the prompt the dot
GitHub slash prompts folder.
Run.
For some reason it's copying them over
there.
So a lot of this is going to be 'cause I
merged in Chris's work.
So while I was pulling, I said not the.
Doing a lot of Chris's work.
Right.
All right, so let's see.
Waiting for Copilot to pick it up,
but I don't know if it's actually started
on it. Yeah,
it looks like it has 2 minutes ago.
So let's die.
Creating a plan. See what that.
Verification and then reading the code.
Store comments.
So it looks like it's adding comments.
So we'll have to see what it decide that
I'm thinking there and if we go back to.
Uh, this one.
You can also see that it started the
review, but it started a while ago.
So it's reserving those files.
So it once it looks like a unit test.
It's like a things that found an issue.
We add the comments,
the correct comment for the counter room.
All right.
OK. So that's proceeding.
Still thinking about that code review,
so put any comments in.
Looks like I might have requested.
A second code review.
Alright, so who's, uh,
working on something else? How's it going?
I'm just waiting with bated breath for
copilot.
Yeah.
And it's done.
All right.
So this is all four, right?
That's right.
And you're not sharing your screen if
just a heads up.
All right, I'll do that then.
All right, starting my screen.
Was there a specific extension people
were using to review?
Because I I I want to I wanted Copilot to
to fetch and and review the the PR that I
had created.
But it's telling me there's no specific
tools available for it.
Was there a specific extension people
were using to do that? I thought maybe,
Dan, you were able to see that.
Well, I have the pro account up on GitHub.
I don't know if that's why,
but I I just went to the PR and.
You know you can just assign it or you
you can assign it to copilot or some
button like that.
Well, sorry,
I meant like copilot on my local like I
there's some unresolved comments and so I
just wanted it to go and fetch the the PR,
pull in the comments and and work on them.
Oh yeah,
I I I opened the PR in in VS code so then
you can add that to your context.
You can tell it to, you know,
address all the issues.
I think we had to manually resolve them.
Once at a time.
But um.
I had we have an I had an extension to
for GitHub to look at PRS.
Yeah, there's a GitHub extension.
Oh, GitHub pull requests extension.
It's aptly named.
Yeah.
OK. Thanks guys.
The only comment on that last copilot
review was Providence metadata in the
OK.
package Jason file.
I think that's good to merge.
All right, that sounds good.
It sounds like that we need to.
Look at our instruction files to see you
know there's a call out explicitly that
when it generates particular files what
what it needs to include but.
Yeah.
Let's go. Let's go ahead and merge it.
I'm answering a question from Al in the
the Q&
A you asked about the the PRD file.
All right,
so this is a question about you know how
we go about in our projects,
you know creating that that requirements
file.
Cause if you remember yesterday we we
asked AI to you know to create a
requirements document after invoking the.
The the the agent for the business
analyst and or the project product
manager,
we asked it to go ahead and create a.
A requirements document for a web-based
calculator application.
You're you're you're probably not in a
situation where you can ask it to to
create a an application for a problem
domain as as as generically as we were
able to yesterday.
So it's gonna be essentially on, you know,
on you and your team to to build those
requirements documents as in order to
inform the A I about what that problem
domain is and and what it what the
application is intended to do.
What are the the things that need to be
that need to be added to the application
in order to, you know,
to improve its functionality?
And so that's something that AI can
assist you with.
But it it, you know,
it doesn't have the the subject matter
expertise that you know you have within
your organization to actually build those
kinds of documents.
Any other questions that I can answer?
How's things going?
I was looking at a way for it to.
It can read the GitHub review comments,
but it can't resolve each of them after
it implements them and does another
commit to the PR.
Do you know of any way to do that?
No, I don't know of any way to do that.
I tried to tell it to do it and it said
that.
Let me go back and see here.
It tried to run the a command,
but then it said this.
And the command it tried to run after
that failed.
So I I was just it's probably a web UI
interaction that it's not able to handle.
Yeah,
I was gonna ask the ask the copilot if
there was such a way.
So the prompt would be can the the GitHub
Hmm.
CLI resolve.
Oh, that's.
Um, any you are.
Looks like I need to refresh my.
Well, it seems to think so.
OK, let me try that one.
So let me post that to the chat,
the prompt.
O That was the prompt I used.
There's a way of listing them.
So.
Let me close this down.
Give me a little bit more space here.
And get to the terminal window.
And.
And it looks like I've got my access
tokens restricted in order to do that.
So I would do that and get in GitHub.
I'd need to go to my personal access
token and and either modify the existing
token or create a new one with the proper
permissions.
This is why I was suggesting I'm creating
one that was a classic token that.
There's too many permissions potentially,
but.
For this, for our purposes,
it should be fine.
So with merge complex, um.
Is there what's the best way to to
resolve them?
Just I mean I in VS code I merged
Greenfield back to my branch and I just
in the so there's like 3 files that have
conflicts. So I just asked VS code,
you know there's merge conflicts,
fix them.
Is this the best way?
Is there another way to do it like on
Yeah.
this on GitHub itself?
Or is this like kind of the best the best
way to do it?
Yeah, yeah, I either, you know,
let I take a look at it first and then if
they can't resolve them,
I'll go into the merge editor and and and
fix them themselves or open up the file
and see where the merge conflicts are.
You know, usually I I find that.
Either I accepting the current changes or.
Oh, what's the other one?
They accept the existing changes that it
resolves the problem.
Mhm.
Yeah, I know it.
Christy.
Yeah, I don't know JavaScript too well.
I don't wanna be trying to parse through
all this JavaScript JavaScript code.
Right, right. Yeah. And again,
I think this goes to the architecture
that we're implementing.
Mhm.
That we, you know, I think it would.
My approach might be to go back to the
vertical slice implementation
documentation and make sure that it was
creating a vertical slice that it
dictates or requires that these be.
As isolated as we can make the code bases
so that that the code that we're writing
in our individual slices doesn't require
any significant amount of merging.
Now we'll take, you know,
we have a very simple architecture here.
It might be easier to manage if we were
dealing.
With something that wasn't just a a
static web page with just JavaScript
behind it,
but we're dealing with something that was
a little bit more complex.
It might be a little bit easier to
separate things into separate modules.
All right then.
Let's go back to our issues.
We're still working. Oh,
it looks like we got.
For merge,
so it's just we're looking for three.
Yeah, just pushed some updates to that.
Yeah.
It's.
I think the last issue is 1 related to.
Uh, yeah, the provenance metadata.
OK.
Do you need another review or do you
think that you're in good shape?
Yeah, I think it's fun.
All right,
let's go ahead and push that one and we
can then move on to the next slice.
They'll merge it now.
All right, that looks good.
All right, so uh, looks like.
That's done. It's our pull requests.
There's no open pull request,
which is good.
So let me know how things are going with
what you're implementing now, and then,
if I can help you, there's something that.
You want to share?
I have a question. Are you gonna,
you know, talk a little bit about,
you know,
like what's takeaways just to kind of
summarize and like what's the best way to
try to incorporate this in in our
organizations or in our coding? I mean,
I know every organization is different,
but.
You know,
just a way to what's the best way to
digest all this and and to um.
To try to bring some of these some of
this into our our daily work.
Well, I think you know,
I think the first step would be is to
build your instruction files to govern
your development process.
So you can take a look at what we created
in terms of those core instructions,
you know those you you could potentially.
Include you know directly into your your
your into your process right now just to
to to guide creating additional AI
generated output and to generate
instruction files and agents and.
Prompts.
So those are harmless and they won't do
anything unless you actually add. Um.
And I should actually ask AI to generate
some additional files.
You can then you know,
of course you know you might want to
review them just to make sure that
there's something in there in terms of
how the provenance is generated or the
metadata information, whether any of that.
You either need it or you can remove it
or if you want to expand on it.
So once you have those core files as a
part of your solution and part of your
projects,
you can then work on the technology
specific pieces. So which is what we did,
you know early yesterday was to ask the
AI to produce instruction files that
would.
Govern that and then I would.
I would then do some prompts that would
identify where your current code base
deviates from those standards and
conventions that you have in your
instruction files.
That would be that would point out some
technical debt that you would.
Want to put in your backlog that you
would like to to get resolved and you can
then you know start to use AI to kind of
address those those issues.
So that would be my the the like the the
second step you know is to.
Start to use it to interrogate the code
base and look for look for ways that you
can you can basically build that backlog
of technical debt that you want to try to
pay down.
If you're working on Greenfield then it's
it's it's it's kind of a similar process
where you're.
Bringing in the core instructions and
then adding in technically specific ones
for the technology stacks that you intend
to use and then you know,
building out your requirements documents
and going from there.
On the on the brownfield side,
you know you if you have existing
requirements documents,
I would point AI to them and ask ask it
to examine those and see where those
documents could be improved or those
where there are.
No conflicting instructions or things
that are not clear and see if you can
improve those requirements documents to
get to a a point that they're usable by A
I in order to produce artifacts and then.
And then if you have AI to create,
you know, new features, you can actually,
you know,
use a a agent to build the requirements
for a new feature and break it down into
a user stories and use cases.
And then basically into implementation
prompts that you can then use to to guide
the implementation of that particular
feature.
So you know it's really kind of building,
building on top of the the instructions
that you initially create and then get
work your way to a point where.
Where you have a clear and a clear intent
that you can give to the give to the AI
in order to to to do the implementation
and you can do those kinds of test
implementations and like take a look at
the output and make it an iterative
process. So if you don't.
If you don't like any part of what it's
generating,
you can then go back to your instruction
files and your prompt files and your
agents and and provide it with additional
direction and content and that will allow
allow you to go back and reproduce that
same output and and get.
An improved implementation,
and that's a very common practice,
very similar to iterating on a code base.
You're iterating on a set of guardrails
and problems in order for you to produce
the output that you're interested in.
So and then that becomes basically you
you really kind of just build on top of
that every time that you have a new
capability that you wanted to to
implement,
you can then create the instruction files
around that.
And then and then utilize those
instruction files then to produce the
output. So for example,
if we wanted to deploy this application
into a a a into the cloud,
we could create instruction files for
building a pipeline in the technology
that you're going to be using for the.
Deployment,
whether that be Azure DevOps or GitHub or
or your git bucket or whatever the tool
is that you're using and then build.
Instruction files for.
Actually creating the the infrastructure
using Terraform or Bicep or whatever the
technology is that you're Illumi or
whatever you're using to build that so
that you now have the ability to
provision resources in the cloud and then
deploy resources.
Into that infrastructure and then run
tests against that to make sure that it's
actually working.
So by by identifying a particular
capability that you're trying to enable,
you can build the instruction files
around that and the prompts around that.
And the agents around that assist you in
actually accomplishing those tasks.
Is that making sense?
Yeah, yeah, it is.
All right, good to hear.
All right, where do we stand?
We got anything ready to showcase?
I don't have anything to showcase,
but I do want to comment on on what you
were just talking about this morning
before training.
Sure.
I I just grabbed your generate
instructions prompt that you have in the
repo and I applied that to.
Right.
One of our existing projects,
I pulled the two of the UI apps in the
back end API into a VS code workspace and
just ran that prompt and it did a an
excellent job of creating Angular
instructions, API design, C# logging.
It it noticed that it was using the
repository pattern and so I felt like
that was a really good starting point
that now I can take these files to the
rest of the team and say let's start
refining these because we do a lot of
angular and.net development.
So let's start refining these kind of
Mhm.
like higher level ones that we can then.
Bring into all of our other projects and
that was a super easy way to to get
something tangible to, you know,
start working from.
Right.
I mean I think that's that's like an
excellent point where you're you know
with very limited amount of effort on
your part,
you're producing something very tangible
that that that people can see value in
and then then as you actually then as you
take those and that.
Those instruction files that were created
and you go to the team with them and
refine them.
That process will engage the rest of the
team into understanding what those things
are. You then can turn around and say,
all right,
so now that we've agreed on these
instruction files for Angular or whatever
the technology is.
That you're you're invoking.
You can have a look at those code bases
and say, OK,
tell me where those code bases deviate
from these or don't conform to these
instructions that we've just agreed that
we want to be able to adopt.
That then is part of your backlog, right?
You now have identified areas where you
can improve the code base with with not a
lot of, a lot of,
potentially not a lot of effort,
and then all of a sudden be able to run
that same prompt again and then find out
that it's that that you don't have any.
Any of those types of issues that you
need to address, then your code base is,
you know,
closer to being Evergreen as opposed to,
you know, something that you don't.
It's something that's, you know,
varies in terms of its implementation
across the board.
Nice. Yep. Thanks.
Yeah, yeah, right. For for Brownfield,
to me it's like all about creating those
instruction files in particularly because
they're the ones that that you can use to
evaluate your current implementation and
without touching any of the code base.
You can you can get an enormous amount of
value out of just understanding where you
stand and what you're facing and and
being able to surface that information to
the organization so that they understand
then.
What you're dealing with and they can you
know and then you can then the next step
would be to verify how how rapidly you
can address those types of issues and
that will go a ways towards getting the
the the teams that are in charge of
assigning resources to prod.
To to to to grant more,
more to bring more technical that into
the into the mix so that you can use a I
to to try to tear down that pay down that
technical debt.
I mean that's to brownfield it's all
about you know paying down technical debt.
You know, once you've got,
once you get to a more of an Evergreen
position,
then you're then you're essentially want
to just make sure that your instruction
files will keep your code base Evergreen.
And you know we could we you know after
implementing a few of these slices we can
go back and we can ask you know is this
code that we've created is it is it
Evergreen and what would improvements
that we need to make and that would be
good information to take back into our
instruction files and into our.
Into our process that we're using to
generate artifacts to try to keep it
Evergreen and continue to keep it
Evergreen.
All right.
And where are we sending anything?
To look at yet.
I a pull request I made.
I did it against main.
I did it against main so I had to close
it.
Now I'm making it again for issue for
issue 7.
OK.
So now I'm it's copilot's reviewing it.
Another question like what about thoughts
on like politics around using AI?
You know,
and it's such like doing it this way,
such a different way that this
organization I consult with, they do it.
I I almost can't even envision them.
You know, embracing, embracing this,
it would be such a different mindset and
all the different developers. And yeah,
and I think it can get pretty messy if I
if we have like, you know,
10 different developers trying to make
Well.
these instructions and prompts and this
and that I.
So I don't know,
just any thoughts on that or anybody have
Mhm.
thoughts?
Anybody else have a thought on this?
So my my perspective would be it's a
really a confidence game, right?
You're really trying to expose the
organization to the process and I would
focus on the read aspects of it and not
the modifications.
That we're using a I to help us better
understand the code base that we're in.
We're using a I to help us identify
technical debt that we need to pay down
and and and go through that those
exercises that we've gone through in the
brownfield side of.
The the development process to basically
just get people accustomed to the idea
that we're using AI in a limited way
within the code base to help us improve
the the state of the application and.
Then it becomes a matter of.
Do you, you know,
you could take an approach that's more
iterative that says, OK,
I've got these instruction files and I've
created them and it's produced all of
this.
It's identified all those technical debt.
You can then leverage those same
instruction files when you're working on
a particular.
Piece of code to help you generate it and
then but then you follow the normal
processes for incorporating that that
that code into the into the code base.
I mean the the the main the main approach
would be.
We're not treating AI generated code any
different demo code that any of the
developers would write.
It would go through the same procedures,
the same review and this and the and the
like and then this is slowly.
And get people accustomed to the idea
that that the the A I generated code is
actually it doesn't cause them any any
issues.
But you know so if you do that then I
think that that will help build the the
confidence that you need.
In order for you to expand that that
process.
The other way that you could do this is
you find people in the group that are
that are.
Open to the idea of doing it and then
interested in learning some of the things
that we've been discussing here and then
and and showing them.
That's kind of how a lot of things in
software development get.
Promulgated to the organization and
somebody learns it and then starts to to
advocate for it and spread it throughout
the rest of the organization. You know,
you know how far you be you're able to
take it will be the, you know,
basically based on the the speed that
they're willing to.
Absorb that that change, Yeah,
because I mean,
if you were thinking this in in terms of,
you know, how you would, you know,
if you were to try to steer an entire
organization towards using this kind of
approach, it would take, you know,
a great deal of training and.
And just, you know,
making people feel comfortable about that
process. We, you know,
I think the idea is that as as time goes
on, it's.
The A I the A I generated code is is
going to go through a process that is as
rigorous or more rigorous than the than
the process that human written code will
go through and the the businesses are
going to start to.
Focus more on the using AI to generate
the code because it's it's going through
a process that they they understand and
they they understand the rigor behind it
in order for it to be implemented and as
the tools improve and as the review tools
approve and the processes improve.
I at some point,
and I don't know when that would be,
it's going to be looked upon that human
written code in some cases is not as
preferable as seeing the code being had
that had been generated by A and going
through the.
The rigor that the AI that we've been
showing that that we can put AI code
through in order for us to be able to
make it acceptable. So I think over time.
The politics will will switch over to
favor AI generated code than to having to
write all the code by hand.
OK, that's helpful.
Other questions?
Anything else?
Anybody got something to look at?
All right.
So I heard that someone was using cursor.
Anybody else using different AI tools
than Copilot?
I use I use cloud code and then just two
days ago I downloaded and was using anti
gravity which which they right now they
have a what seems to be a very generous.
Usage limit that I was not able to hit
the other day when I was playing with
several different options and it's very
familiar.
It's it seems to be a fork of of VS code.
Those those two.
Well, that's interesting. Anybody else?
I haven't used it,
but one member of our group I think is
using Rider with the plugin for it and it
seems to work OK from what he says.
Is anybody using Visual Studio with
Copilot?
Yeah, I've been, I've been listening.
I I do when I have to work on legacy
projects, but.
Yeah, I'm I'm.
Like.net 48 projects, I'll do that,
but it's not often.
Does someone else have a comment?
I think a couple of people did. Yeah,
I also use Visual Studio because we have
some that frame 4.
8 and also I just prefer a little bit
better for like more of the back end,
but it's a lot slower I found.
Then VS code.
So I try to do as much as I can if I'm
doing AI stuff in VS code,
but if I'm like really like developing or
looking through code and reviewing other
people's code,
I like to use Visual Studio.
Anyone else have a comment?
I've been using a 2026 insider and it's a
lot faster than 2022.
I basically threw that away,
but we use it because it's nice because
it integrates with the debugger and so if
you're having a database issues,
it can actually interface with the
debugger when you hit a breakpoint.
You use that to pull context out of it.
So and we also deal with solution based
and that in VS code seems to be a pain
most of the time.
So I'd say probably 60% of the time I'm
in Visual Studio.
OK.
Anyone else want to contribute?
Well,
that did remind me of something that
might be interesting to talk about in
that if you're working on a web
application.
Wanna bring up where's chats?
Is that?
Let me see if I can get it to do this.
Let me create a new chat here.
And say um.
Open now.
Simple.
Browser.
I can.
I think I can get that to one of the
views, but the idea is.
That there's a browser that's built into
Via's code.
And.
The URL. Um
Say I get home.
Directorable.
There must be something that's blocking
that,
but the idea is that you can bring up a
page in the simple browser.
That could be something that it that
you're working on,
and then you could add elements to the
chat so you could find something here
that.
It's on the page that you want to
actually have the chat look at.
You can actually select it and then that
will actually paste that particular piece
from the simple browser into the chat
window and then you could add a add
something to the prompt that indicates.
What needs to change about that
particular piece of the browser that's in
the browser and it will then focus its
attention on that specific piece.
And that was very handy when I was
building that AI resources page.
Um.
In order for it to improve the UI was a
matter of just bringing the page up in
the browser and then using it to identify
where the where in the page that it
actually needed to work. I'm not sure.
Let's.
There must be something here.
Send elements to the chat.
That's what we want to do.
Yeah, I mean.
Let me see if I can troubleshoot this.
Well, we have a web page. Let's see.
But.
Um, let me.
Get the latest code from the green.
So let me push these changes first.
And then get down the pull the rest of
the changes. Hopefully no merge conflicts.
All right, that looks good.
So that would mean that we have.
There's our code.
You have uh where? Where is the web app?
Arizona.
Quorums.
The you say where is the web app?
Yeah, I'm looking for the.
It's in the web calculator folder.
Well, I do.
And there's index, so let me open that.
All right,
so it wants to start a web server.
And now we have it here.
We're going to add an element to chat,
we we hit start and then it'll go through
and say if we want to do something with
the display window,
we could capture that and then it would
have an element screenshot here in the in
the context that we then can use.
As at a prompt and we could then ask it
to do something significant, you know,
like you know,
change the font or change the the,
the color, change the placement,
whatever we wanted to we have whatever
issue that we wanted to address and then
it would take the.
We take that as a a prompt and try to try
to do that implementation for us.
So this is I think very,
very useful tool to take advantage of if
you're doing any kind of web development
to try to.
Rapidly improve the the work that you're
doing.
All right. How we doing? Anything else?
I'm still trying to merge and.
Uh,
apply the PR comments that from GoPilot.
All right, Chris is working on me.
Also try to pay attention to what you're
showing so.
All right, no worries, no worries. I mean,
you know, you'll have this repository,
Look.
you know, you know, available to you.
And so you can at your leisure,
you can go and try to implement as many
slices as you want to implement and.
I think get additional experience on a on
a code base to try to in terms of
actually you know writing new features
and getting AI to produce the code and
going through the review process and
getting and getting approval from that.
I think all I think all valuable
exercises.
That you can do and there's plenty of
plenty of material in the issues that
that were created and some of those
implementations are are not they're not
very they're not simple like the the
beginning ones that we have here with the
calculator.
They get much more complex as you get
deeper.
Into the the dependency tree and so you
could take a look at.
Doing that kind of experimentation and
that's a good safe way to do it because
it's in this project and.
And therefore it's, uh, you know,
you can make as many modifications as you
need.
Yeah.
Are we gonna get all the slides 'cause we
had one or two,
but then they're not there and then I
No other all the slides are in the in
this project.
don't know.
If you pulled it down you should see them.
They're um, they're PDF files.
Uh, which?
Is it in the main branch?
Yeah, it'll be in the main branch.
The fundamental slides are in the main
branch.
I think the Greenfield slides are in the
Greenfield branch and the Brownfield
slides are in the Brownfield branch.
Oh, OK,
so there's there's three sets of slides.
Yeah, one one for the the first day,
one for the brownfield 2 days and then
one for the Greenfield 2 days.
OK. Yeah,
they're in each of their own branches, OK.
Other questions?
Recordings. Yeah, those will be.
Those will be sent out.
You'll get an e-mail. I'll switch to the.
The last slide,
since that's one of the topics there.
So.
All right, so basically to wrap this up,
everybody at code,
thanks you for attending.
I appreciate your attention and your your
input.
It was it was a valuable core input for
building this course and my.
Expect an e-mail with links to those
recordings and also a link to a survey
and I would appreciate any feedback that
you have both positive and negative.
It would help us improve this course
going forward. Just so you're aware,
we're also building.
A cloud code course.
So if you're interested in further
information or training about cloud code,
let us know and we'll have a we have a
special offer for people interested in in
beta testing the course material.
Also consider booking time for mentoring.
I do this with other clients that have
taken the training and we spend an hour
or two a week reviewing the the work that
they've been able to accomplish.
And I give them guidance in terms of how
they how they can proceed and answer any
questions that they have in terms of
their their use of A I in in their
environments with one of them we're going
through and building.
Work instructions.
And.
To help them create a something that is
audible,
auditable and something that they can use
to document the process and confirm that
they're conforming to it and then we're
gonna proceed.
To start to actually use it to build out
a a a either.
We haven't haven't decided yet,
but whether it's going to be a
modification to a brownfield app or a
rewrite of the application using
Greenfield techniques.
So if you're interested in.
And getting a little assistance,
it wouldn't be very expensive and you
would be able to take some,
get some guidance as you're going along
to help you, you know,
get yourself out of sticky spots and then
I'll.
Um.
And then if there are any final questions,
I'd be happy to answer them now.
There's a question about attending a
copilot conference in San Diego. I can't.
I'm not committed to doing it at the
moment,
but it'd be something I'm very interested
in doing.
There was another GitHub conference.
Earlier in the later in last year that I
wasn't able to make, but I yeah,
definitely interested in attending those
kinds of events and just a final thing on
code is that.
You know code is we we we do this
training.
We also can help you with consulting if
you have the bigger efforts that you
would need some guidance on either
architectural guidance or implementation
assistance and then there's also the.
The uh.
The staffing side of things,
if you actually need to beef up your your,
your,
your organization in terms of just having
additional resources available to help
you with your your projects,
code is also available to help you with
that.
And the the last thing is a a code a
magazine and in your your your e-mail you
would should receive a an invitation to.
I need an invitation to a free
subscription to the Code magazine,
so look for that as well.
So I'm free to answer any other questions
that you have.
Otherwise,
I I really appreciate your attendance and
I really hope this was something that you
can use regularly in your day-to-day work.
Yeah, lots of good stuff. Thanks, John.
You're welcome. I'm glad you liked.
You're welcome.
Thanks, John. Thanks, everybody.
Yeah, thank you.
Thanks, John.
It's good meeting you all.
I look forward to running into you in the
Thank you, John.
Thanks, John.
future.
Thank you. Thank you, John.
Take care.
Thank you, John.
Thanks, John. That was really great.
I'm glad you liked it.
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
Thanks for answering all my questions,
John. Appreciate it.
I mean, no problem. I was glad to do it.
Yeah. See you around. Take care. Bye, bye.
All right. All right. So you're on.
OK.
All right. Thanks, Otto.
Thank you too, John.
I think, yeah,
I think we can stop the recording here.
I'll do that.